[
  {
    "id": "a0001",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The slow twitch muscle  fibres are particularly  beneficial in this sport",
    "correctAnswer": "Running",
    "optionValues": [
      "Weight lifting",
      "Running",
      "Boxing ",
      "Gymnastics"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0002",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The energy currency of the cell is",
    "correctAnswer": "Adenosine tri-phosphate",
    "optionValues": [
      "Adenosine tri-phosphate",
      "Adenosine tri potasium",
      "Amino tri- phosphate",
      "Alanine tri - phosphate"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0003",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Rahul goes for one hour of walk everyday what would be the best drink for him to drink after exercise.",
    "correctAnswer": "Plain water",
    "optionValues": [
      "Glucon D",
      "Plain water",
      "Sugar cane juice",
      "Sports drinks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0004",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Creatine phopshate is used as an energy source in which of the following activities",
    "correctAnswer": "Sprinting",
    "optionValues": [
      "Sprinting",
      "Walking",
      "Writing",
      "Sleeping"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0005",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following is a very good source of Vitamin C",
    "correctAnswer": "Amla",
    "optionValues": [
      "Sweetlime",
      "Papaya",
      "Amla",
      "Milk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0006",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following foods  has a low glycemic index ?",
    "correctAnswer": "Soyabean",
    "optionValues": [
      "Bread",
      "Watermelon",
      "Potato",
      "Soyabean"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0007",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "What are the effects of excess protein intake ?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Dehydration",
      "Kidney damage",
      "Bone loss",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0008",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "In a football match which of the energy system is used to  obtain energy ?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "ATP-CP system",
      "Anerobic glycolysis",
      "Aerobic glycolysis",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0009",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "What is the daily protein requirement for a normal person is ?",
    "correctAnswer": "1g/Kg of body weight/d",
    "optionValues": [
      "1g/Kg of body weight/d",
      "1.2g/Kg of body weight/d",
      "1.5g/Kg of body weight/d",
      "0.7g/Kg of body weight/d"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00010",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "What is the predominant nutrient present in the daily Indian diet",
    "correctAnswer": "Carbohdyrates",
    "optionValues": [
      "Vitamins and Minerals",
      "Carbohydrates",
      "Proteins",
      "Fats"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00011",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Our body needs vitamins and minerals because they",
    "correctAnswer": "Help in metabolic reactions of the body",
    "optionValues": [
      "Give energy to our body",
      "Help in metabolic reactions of the body",
      "Insulate body organs",
      "Help to maintain body temperature"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00012",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Calculate the BMI of a 40year old woman with body weight of 60Kg and height of 160cm",
    "correctAnswer": "23.43",
    "optionValues": [
      "25.24",
      "26.34",
      "23.43",
      "27.34"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00013",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The fat which is present in the abdomen is called",
    "correctAnswer": "Non essential Fat",
    "optionValues": [
      "Essential Fat",
      "Non essential Fat",
      "Harmful Fat",
      "Cholesterol"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00014",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The best method to quantitatively assess dietary nutrient intake is",
    "correctAnswer": "24 hour recall method",
    "optionValues": [
      "Food Diary",
      "Quantative Food Frquency Qustionnaire",
      "Qualitative Food Frquency Qustionnaire",
      "24 hour recall method"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00015",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The normal BUN to Creatinin Ratio is",
    "correctAnswer": "10-15:1",
    "optionValues": [
      "10-15:2",
      "1:10-15",
      "10-15:1",
      "2:10-15"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00016",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Iron deficiency leads to this condition",
    "correctAnswer": "Spoon shaped nails",
    "optionValues": [
      "Hair discolouration",
      "Spoon shaped nails",
      "Dry Skin",
      "Brittle Nails"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00017",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "This method identifies the nutrient deficiency much before the clinical signs appear",
    "correctAnswer": "Biochemical assessment",
    "optionValues": [
      "Anthropometrical assessment",
      "Dietary assessment",
      "Biochemical assessment",
      "Clinical assessment"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00018",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The clinical symptom of Vitamin C deficiency is",
    "correctAnswer": "Glossitis",
    "optionValues": [
      "Defective vision",
      "Rickets",
      "Glossitis",
      "Beri Beri"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00019",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Dark adaptation is a functional test to assess the nutritional status of",
    "correctAnswer": "Vitamin A",
    "optionValues": [
      "Vitamin D",
      "Vitamin A",
      "Vitamin K",
      "Vitamin C"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00020",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Energy system for a mid-fielder is mainly",
    "correctAnswer": "Aerobic",
    "optionValues": [
      "ATP-CP",
      "Aerobic",
      "Anaerobic-glycolysis",
      "None-of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00021",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Endurance training enhances which of the following",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Mitochondira no.",
      "Capillariation",
      "Aerobic oxidative enzymes",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00022",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Percent body fat of  runners ranges between",
    "correctAnswer": "7-15%",
    "optionValues": [
      "20-25%",
      "25-30%",
      "10-15%",
      "7-15%"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00023",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Carbohydrate loading is suitable for which sports",
    "correctAnswer": "Triathlon",
    "optionValues": [
      "Triathlon",
      "Kabbadi",
      "Goal keepers in football",
      "Boxing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00024",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Weight cycling- weight gain and loss is common in which of the following sport",
    "correctAnswer": "Taekwondo",
    "optionValues": [
      "Taekwondo",
      "Archery",
      "Kho-Kho",
      "Tennis "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00025",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a symptom of Female athlete triad",
    "correctAnswer": "Weight gain",
    "optionValues": [
      "Menstrual dysfunction",
      "Osteoporosis",
      "Weight gain",
      "Low energy availability"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00026",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Hypo-natremia is caused due to the drop in levels of which mineral",
    "correctAnswer": "Na",
    "optionValues": [
      "K",
      "Ca",
      "Na",
      "Cl"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00027",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Protein requirements (g/kg/bw/d) for hockey players",
    "correctAnswer": "1.2-2",
    "optionValues": [
      "1.2-2",
      "1-1.5",
      "1.5-2.5",
      "2-2.5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00028",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "What are the Key supplements that can be used by Kabbadi players ?",
    "correctAnswer": "Protein, creatine",
    "optionValues": [
      "Protein, creatine",
      "Protein, multivitamin",
      "Calcium, electrolytes",
      "Creatine, calcium"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00029",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Hydration opportunities in team sports in match include",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Half-times",
      "Substitutions",
      "Technical time-outs",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00030",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following nutrient does not provide energy ?",
    "correctAnswer": "Calcium",
    "optionValues": [
      "Calcium",
      "Protein",
      "Fat",
      "Carbohydrate"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00031",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Sports anaemia results in",
    "correctAnswer": "Decrease in heamatocrit",
    "optionValues": [
      "Increase in heamoglobin",
      "Decrease in blood volume",
      "Decrease in heamatocrit",
      "Increase in serum ferritin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00032",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following components are essential for muscle buiding ?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Resistance Exercise",
      "Protein",
      "Rest",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00033",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following nutrient is essential to increase blood haemoglobin ?",
    "correctAnswer": "Iron",
    "optionValues": [
      "Glucose",
      "Iron",
      "Vitamin A",
      "Phosphorus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00034",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Energy obtained from a meal that contains 25g carbohydrate, 10g protein and 10g fat would be ___________kcal",
    "correctAnswer": "230",
    "optionValues": [
      "360",
      "500",
      "230",
      "150"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00035",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The symptoms of disordered eating are------------ except",
    "correctAnswer": "Eating balanced diet",
    "optionValues": [
      "Eating balanced diet",
      "Induce vomitting",
      "Use of laxatives",
      "Voluntary starvation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00036",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "____________ is example of empty calorie food",
    "correctAnswer": "Potato chips",
    "optionValues": [
      "Tomato soup",
      "Aloo paratha",
      "Potato chips",
      "Chicken sandwich"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00037",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Choose the best meal option that an athlete can eat during training",
    "correctAnswer": "Banana",
    "optionValues": [
      "Sprouts",
      "Cucumber",
      "Soup",
      "Banana"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00038",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "______________ is example of modifiable risk factor of chronic diseases",
    "correctAnswer": "Lifestyle",
    "optionValues": [
      "Age",
      "Race",
      "Lifestyle",
      "Gender"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00039",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following statement is false",
    "correctAnswer": "Physical activity is subcatagory of exercise",
    "optionValues": [
      "Physical activity is subcatagory of exercise",
      "Excersise is stuctured activity",
      "Excersise can be repeated",
      "Exercise can be planned"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00040",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "_______ is example of power sport",
    "correctAnswer": "Throwing",
    "optionValues": [
      "Throwing",
      "Hockey",
      "Shooting",
      "Swimming"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00041",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Vitamins that works as an antioxidants in the body",
    "correctAnswer": "Vitamin E",
    "optionValues": [
      "Vitamin B",
      "Vitamin D",
      "Vitamin E",
      "Vitamin K"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00042",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Badminton is a  sport that originated in this city of India",
    "correctAnswer": "Pune",
    "optionValues": [
      "Panaji",
      "Mumbai",
      "Bangalore",
      "Pune"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00043",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "What is the best time to take a Vitamin C supplement by a sports person ?",
    "correctAnswer": "With Post-training meal",
    "optionValues": [
      "With Pre-training meal or Breakfast",
      "With Post-training meal",
      "At bedtime or Dinner",
      "Empty stomach – on waking up"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00044",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Whey and casein are protein supplements- when can you use them?- Choose the correct statement :",
    "correctAnswer": "Whey is ideal for post-training, and casein is ideal for pre-training.",
    "optionValues": [
      "Whey and casein should not be taken pre-training.",
      "Whey and casein should not be taken post-training.",
      "Whey is ideal for pre-training, and casein is ideal for post-training.",
      "Whey is ideal for post-training, and casein is ideal for pre-training."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00045",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Who can face the consequences of Doping ?",
    "correctAnswer": "Athletes and Athlete Supporting Personnel",
    "optionValues": [
      "Only Athletes",
      "Athletes and Athlete Supporting Personnel",
      "Only Athlete Supporting Personnel",
      "There are no consequences of doping"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00046",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "A good sports drink provides",
    "correctAnswer": "6-8% carbohydrates with some electrolytes",
    "optionValues": [
      "6-8% carbohydrates with some electrolytes",
      "More of electrolytes, with small amounts of carbohydrates",
      "Only vitamins and minerals",
      "Only water"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00047",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following supplements can make the training session feel easier ?",
    "correctAnswer": "Caffeine",
    "optionValues": [
      "Vitamin E",
      "Caffeine",
      "Glutamine",
      "Calcium"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00048",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following supplement is recommended during a training session or competition ?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sports drinks",
    "optionValues": [
      "Sports drinks",
      "Vitamin E",
      "Creatine",
      "Iron"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00049",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which supplement is known as a Nitric oxide booster ?",
    "correctAnswer": "Arginine",
    "optionValues": [
      "Creatine",
      "Carnitine",
      "Arginine",
      "BCAA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00050",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct ?",
    "correctAnswer": "Supplements use is associated with doping risk",
    "optionValues": [
      "All supplements are listed on the WADA Prohibited list",
      "Supplements are very safe and can be used without any precaution",
      "Use of Supplements are safe from doping risk",
      "Supplements use is associated with doping risk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00051",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following supplement is recommended during a training session or competition ?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sports drinks",
    "optionValues": [
      "Sports drinks",
      "Vitamin E",
      "Creatine",
      "Iron"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a00052",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "What is the primary benefit of an Arginine supplement ?",
    "correctAnswer": "Increased blood flow",
    "optionValues": [
      "Immunity",
      "Increased blood flow",
      "Haemoglobin synthesis",
      "Bone formation"
    ]
  }
]